Office of Faculty Affairs at the Friedman School of Nutrition Science and Policy Records UA242
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Office of Faculty Affairs at the Friedman School of Nutrition Science and Policy Records
1983 -- 2013
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Office of Faculty Affairs, Friedman School of Nutrition Science and Policy
UA242
8.4 Linear Feet
This collection documents the administration and work of the Office of Faculty Affairs at the Friedman School of Nutrition Science. Also included is documentation of individual centers and programs, such as the International Food and Nutrition Center, the Famine Center, and the Agriculture, Food, and Environment program.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in 4 series: Office files; Meeting minutes and agendas; Course files and curriculum development; and 2016 accessions.
Custodial History
This collection was created in April 2016.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents the administration and work of the Office of Faculty Affairs, including strategic planning, policies and procedures, memos, Board of Trustees correspondence, Dean's files, committee minutes, and curriculum development files. Also included is documentation of individual centers and programs, such as the International Food and Nutrition Center, the Famine Center, and the Agriculture, Food, and Environment program.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the Office of Faculty Affairs of the Friedman School, 2016.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Faculty; Curriculum and Instruction
- Office files, 1994 -- 2010; UA242.001; 1.2 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series documents the administration of the Office of Faculty Affairs, including strategic planning, memos, Board of Trustees correspondence, and International Food and Nutrition Center records.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by subject, as received from the Office of Faculty Affairs.
  Conditions Governing Access
  20 years from date of creation.
  - Strategic planning, memos, Trustees, IFNC, 1994 -- 2010; UA242.001.001 (Box 1)
    Strategic planning, memos, Board of Trustees correspondence, International Food and Nutrition Center records.
- Meeting minutes and agendas, 1990 -- 2010; UA242.002; 2.4 Linear Feet
  This series includes meeting minutes and agendas for the Faculty, Curriculum and Degrees Committee, and the Committee on Committees, as well as related task forces.
  This series is arranged by committee, as received from the Office of Faculty Affairs.
  - Faculty and faculty handbook project, 1990 -- 2006; UA242.002.002 (Box 2)
    Meeting minutes and agendas of the Faculty, 1990-2006; records related to the faculty handbook project, 2006.
  - Faculty meetings, Curriculum and Degrees Committee, Committee on Committees, 1997 -- 2010; UA242.002.003 (Box 3)
    Meeting minutes and agendas of the Faculty, 1997-2009; Curriculum and Degrees Committee, 1997-2010; and Committee on Committees, 1998-2008.
- Course files and curriculum development, 1984 -- 2010; UA242.003; 2.4 Linear Feet
  This series documents courses and curriculum development, including development of programs such as the Agriculture, Food, and Environment program and the Famine Center. Also included are academic integrity polices, other policies and procedures, graduate questionnaires, and NRC assessment records.
  - Course files, NRC assessment, Famine Center, 1994 -- 2010; UA242.003.004 (Box 4)
  - Academic integrity, policies and procedures, graduate questionnaires, AFE program, 1984 -- 2008; UA242.003.005 (Box 5)
- 2016 accessions, 1983 -- 2013; UA242.004; 2.4 Linear Feet 2 record cartons
  This series is arranged in received order. Within boxes, folders are arranged chronologically.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred by the Office of Faculty Affairs of the Friedman School, 2016, accession 2016.114.
  University records are closed for 20 years from the date of creation. Records older than 20 years that do not pertain to student education, staff and faculty employment and Board of Trustees records are open for research.
  This series contains Curriculum and Degree Committee files from 1983-2013, as well as Dean Kennedy's files from 1999-2005, including files on foundations and funds, grants and proposals, strategic and financial planning, awards, media coverage, reports, and meetings.
  - Curriculum and Degree Committee files, 1983 -- 2013; UA242.004.006; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box data_value_missing_a04c5066bbba5e4d2a370d80697e6069, Box 6)
  - Dean's files: Kennedy, 1995 -- 2009; UA242.004.007; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box data_value_missing_a04c5066bbba5e4d2a370d80697e6069, Box 7)